Preliminary Guide to the Randall Hinshaw Papers, 1930-1995 RL.00548
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Randall Hinshaw papers
1930-1995
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hinshaw, Randall Weston
RL.00548
13.5 Linear Feet
Randall Hinshaw was a professor in economics at the Claremont Graduate School, where he specialized in monetary theory. He founded the Claremont-Bologna Monetary Conference Series. Collection includes correspondence, both personal and economics-related; monetary conference files from the 1960s-1990s; audio and video cassettes and reels of conference talks and proceedings; economics articles and reprints; and some of Hinshaw's early schoolwork and papers from the 1930s-1940s.
10,125 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Randall Hinshaw Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009.
Biographical Note
Randall Hinshaw was a graduate of Occidental College (B.A., 1937; M.A., 1938) and of Princeton University (Ph.D., 1944). After working for the Federal Reserve, NATO, and as a lecturer at a variety of universities in the 1940s and 1950s, Hinshaw joined the faculty of Claremont Graduate School in 1960 as a professor of economics. His specialization was monetary theory, and he authored numerous books on the subject, including Monetary Reform and the Price of Gold (1964), The European Community and American Trade: A Study In Atlantic Economics and Policy (1964), The Unstable Dollar: Domestic and International Issues (1988). He also edited compilations, such as The Economics of International Adjustment (1971). In addition to his teaching and research, Hinshaw founded and was the director of the Bologna-Claremont series of biennial international monetary conferences, beginning in 1967. He organized several conferences through the 1990s, many of which are represented in this collection through correspondence and recordings. These conferences frequently attracted internationally acclaimed economic theorists, including Nobel Prize winners.
Chronology List
May 9, 1915 Born in La Grange, Illinois
1937 A.B., Occidental College
1942-1943 Teaching fellow, Harvard University
1944 Ph.D., Princeton University
1943-1946; 1947-1952 Economist, Division of International Finance, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, Washington, D.C.
1946-1947 Assistant Professor of Economics, Amherst College
June 19, 1949 Married Pearl Electa Stevens
1952-1957 Special advisor on trade and international monetary problems, U.S. Mission to NATO and European Regional Organizations (USRO), Paris
1957-1958 Visiting professor of economics, Yale University
1958-1959 Visiting professor of economics, Oberlin College
1959-1960 Visiting research fellow, Council on Foreign Relations, New York
1960 Appointed professor of economics, Claremont Graduate School
1965-1967, summer 1968, spring 1971 Visiting professor of economics, The Johns Hopkins University (Bologna Center, School of Advanced International Studies)
1967 Founder and director of Bologna-Claremont International Monetary Conference series
1967 Bologna I monetary conference
1971 Bologna II monetary conference
1973 Claremont II monetary conference
1975 Claremont III monetary conference
1977 Frankfurt monetary conference
1980 Hamburg monetary conference
1983 Bologna III monetary conference
1986 Claremont V monetary conference
1994 Claremont VI monetary conference
1995 Bologna IV monetary conference
1997 Claremont VII monetary conference
Collection Overview
Although this collection has not been processed, it consists of several major parts: Hinshaw's early schoolwork, including his BA diploma and his MA thesis from Occidental College; drafts of his books; articles, reprints, and papers from Hinshaw and numerous other economists, dating from the 1940s-1990s; conference materials and correspondence from 1968-1995; correspondence files from 1957-1993, including Hinshaw's exchanges with other leading economists; audiotapes, audioreels, and videotapes of economic conference proceedings and speeches; and other miscellaneous or loose material. Most materials have been refoldered for preservation.
Economics; Sound recordings; Videotapes; Audiotapes; Photographs; Economics -- Congresses; Monetary theory; Claremont Graduate School; Hinshaw, Randall Weston; Hinshaw, Randall Weston
- Accession (2009-0138), 1930s-1995, 10 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  This accession consists of several major parts: Hinshaw's early schoolwork, including his BA diploma and his MA thesis from Occidental College; drafts of his books; articles, reprints, and papers from Hinshaw and numerous other economists, dating from the 1940s-1990s; conference materials and correspondence from 1968-1995; correspondence files from 1957-1993, including Hinshaw's exchanges with other leading economists; audiotapes, audioreels, and videotapes of economic conference proceedings and speeches; and other miscellaneous or loose material.
  - Hinshaw schoolwork, no date (Box 1)
  - Philosophy course, 1934 (Box 1)
  - MA Thesis, Occidental College, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Occidental College BA diploma, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Occidental College publications (Box 1)
  - Office material, 1949 (Box 1)
  - John Parke Young: International Trade and Finance, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Paul Samuelson: Economics: An Introductory Analysis, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper photocopies and clippings (2) (Box 1)
  - International Monetary Issues After the Cold War drafts (3) (Box 1)
  - The World Economy in Transition drafts (Box 1)
  - Wages and Unemployment (Box 1)
  - Royalties (Box 1)
  - Council on Foreign Relations correspondence, 1961-1970 (Box 1)
  - Recommendations (3) (Box 1)
  - Articles, papers, and reprints, undated (2) (Box 1)
  - Articles, papers, and reprints, 1940s (Box 2)
  - Articles, papers, and reprints, 1950s (Box 2)
  - Articles, papers, and reprints, 1960s (Box 2)
  - Articles, papers, and reprints, 1970s (2) (Box 2)
  - Articles, papers, and reprints, 1980s (Box 2)
  - Federal Reserve reprints, 1980s (Box 2)
  - Articles, papers, and reprints, 1990s (Box 2)
  - Loose materials and reprints (Box 2)
  - Pamphlet reprints, 1938-1963 (Box 2)
  - Pamphlet reprints, 1946-1990 (Box 2)
  - Hinshaw: The Papers of Sir Roy Harrod (Box 3)
  - Lord Robbins: Autobiography of an Economist (Box 3)
  - Bologna II-book (Box 3)
  - Book correspondence (3) (Box 3)
  - Gold Conference, 1968 (2) (Box 3)
  - 1968 Monetary Conference and correspondence (Box 3)
  - Monetary Conference general file (Box 3)
  - Conferences (3) (Box 3)
  - The Economics of International Adjustment, 1960s-1970s (Box 3)
  - Monetary Reform and the Price of Gold (Box 3)
  - 1969 correspondence (2) (Box 3)
  - 1973 conferences (2) (Box 3)
  - 1991 Symposium correspondence (incoming) (Box 3)
  - 1994 Dialogue correspondence (incoming and outgoing) (Box 3)
  - Filing (Box 3)
  - Conferences (Box 4)
    - Bologna II (outgoing and incoming), 1971 (Box 4)
    - Claremont II (outgoing, incoming, and general), 1973 (Box 4)
    - Claremont III (incoming, outgoing, budget), 1975 (Box 4)
    - Claremont (outgoing and incoming), 1978 (Box 4)
    - Frankfurt (outgoing, incoming, and general), 1977 (Box 4)
    - Hamburg (travel, incoming, outgoing, and general), 1980 (Box 4)
    - Bologna III (outgoing and incoming), 1983 (Box 5)
    - Claremont V (outgoing, incoming, and general), 1986 (Box 5)
    - 1994 Dialogue (general) (Box 5)
    - Claremont (budget), 1994 (Box 5)
    - Bologna (outgoing and incoming), 1995 (Box 5)
  - Publishers correspondence (Box 5)
  - Correspondence (incoming and outgoing), 1957-1960 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence (incoming and outgoing), 1961-1976 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence (incoming and outgoing), 1977-1993 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 8)
  - Claremont monetary conferences, 1973-1995 (Box 8)
  - Claremont Graduate School newsletters (Box 8)
  - Transcript: Bologna-Claremont conference series (Box 8)
  - Claremont Graduate School (Box 8)
  - National Resource Committee: Consumer Expenditures in teh United States (Box 8)
  - Meeting planning guide (Box 8)
  - Loose photocopies and reprints (Box 8)
  - Reviews of conference books (Box 8)
  - Audiocassettes
    - 1975 Conference (Box 8)
    - Johns Hopkins, 1995 (Box 8)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Audiocassettes, open reels, videotapes (Box 9)
    - Southern Poverty Law Center (Box 9)
    - Council on Foreign Relations (Box 9)
    - Economic conference, 1969 (Box 9)
    - Claremont II (Box 9)
    - Claremont Economics Conference, March 1986 (Box 9)
    - Hinshaw: International Monetary Disorder, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Milton Friedman, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Hamburg International Monetary Conference (Box 9)
    - Harry Johnson (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous research and lecture notes (Box 10)
  - Family Album (Hinshaw family) newsletters, 1930s (Box 10)
  - Clippings (Box 10)
  - Some Questions of Time in Economics (Box 10)
  - Photographs (Box 10)
  - Banking and Monetary Statistics (Box 10)
  - Audiocassettes (Box 10)
  - Audio reels
    - 1971 Conference (Bologna) (Box 10)
    - Claremont II (Box 10)
    - 1973 tapes (reels) (Box 10)